Guide to the Gertrude Stein and Alice B. Toklas Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
MS Vault film 1474 145 92 1721-1726
MS Vault film 1475 146 93-94 1727-1760
Series II. Gertrude Stein Correspondence
MS Vault film 1149 1 95 1761-1790
MS Vault film 1150 2 95-96 1791-1806
MS Vault film 1151 3 96-97 1807-1853
MS Vault film 1152 4 97-98 1854-1880
MS Vault film 1153 5 98-99 1881-1911
MS Vault film 1154 6 99-100 1912-1935
MS Vault film 1155 7 100-101 1936-1972
MS Vault film 1156 8 101-102 1973-1988
MS Vault film 1157 9 102-103 1989-2015
MS Vault film 1158 10 103-104 2016-2067 Folder 2060 has been changed from Dudley, Catharine to Dudley, Caroline.
MS Vault film 1159 11 105-106 2068-2095
MS Vault film 1160 12 106-107 2096-2121
MS Vault film 1161 13 107-108 2122-2155
MS Vault film 1162 14 108-109 2156-2192
MS Vault film 1163 15 109 2193-2216
MS Vault film 1164 16 110-111 2217-2255
MS Vault film 1165 17 111-112 2256-2283 Folder 2267 has been changed to Hugnet, Georges (father of Georges), 1926, 1931.
The letter of 1929 Sep 9 has been moved from folder 2264 to folder 2267.
Folder 2278 has been changed from Imbs, Nella Larsen to Imes, Nella Larsen.
MS Vault film 1166 18 112-113 2284-2319
MS Vault film 1167 19 113-114 2320-2358
MS Vault film 1168 20 114 2359-2390
MS Vault film 1183 21 115 2391-2420
MS Vault film 1184 22 116 2421-2477
MS Vault film 1185 23 117 2478-2523
MS Vault film 1186 24 118-119 2524-2558
MS Vault film 1187 25 119-120 2559-2608 Letters from Man Ray: letter dated 1925 Aug 23 has been corrected to 1922 Aug 23 and refiled chronologically.
One letter from Radcliffe College Library was removed from folder 2579 and filed with folder 2581.
MS Vault film 1198 26 121 2609-2623
MS Vault film 1197 27 122 2624-2648
MS Vault film 1196 28 123 2649-2678
MS Vault film 1229 29 124 2679-2715 In folder 2711, a substituted photocopy was filmed, not the original letter.
MS Vault film 1228 30 125 2716-2729
MS Vault film 1227 31 126 2730-2754
MS Vault film 1230 32 127 2755-2776
MS Vault film 33 128 2777-2811
MS Vault film 1233 34 129 2812-2822
MS Vault film 1234 35 130 2823-2848
MS Vault film 1235 36 131 2849-2884
MS Vault film 1236 37 132 2885-2917
MS Vault film 1237 38 133 2918-2930
MS Vault film 1238 39 134 2931-2962
Series III. Third-Party Letters
MS Vault film 1240 40 135 2962a-3071
Series IV. Alice B. Toklas Correspondence
MS Vault film 1241 41 136-137 3072-3191
MS Vault film 1242 42 137-138 3192-3244
Series V. Personal Papers
MS Vault film 1476 147 139-140 3245-3292
MS Vault film 1477 148 140-141 3293-3332
Series VI. Clippings
MS Vault film 1478 149 142-143 3333-3353
MS Vault film 1479 150 144 3354-3364
MS Vault film 1485 151 145 3365-3372
MS Vault film 1486 152 146 3373-3390
Series VII. Photographs
MS Vault film 1494 153 147-151 3391-3655
MS Vault film 1504 154 152-156 3656-3970
MS Vault film 1514 155 157-161 3971-4247
Series VIII. Artworks & Series IX. Objects
MS Vault film 1521 156 162-166 4248-4306
Oversize
MS Vault film 1584 157 168-169 4308-4334
MS Vault film 1585 158 170-172 4335-4361
MS Vault film 1411 159 144 3354-3364
American literature -- 20th Century; Americans -- France -- History -- 20th Century; Art and literature; Art, Modern -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Cubism and literature; Literature, Experimental; Modernism (Literature); Women authors, American -- 20th Century; Paris (France) -- Intellectual life; Paintings (visual works); Photographic prints; Authors; Man Ray, 1890-1976; Acton, Harold, 1904-1994; Aldrich, Mildred, 1853-1928; Anderson, Sherwood, 1876-1941; Atherton, Gertrude Franklin Horn, 1857-1948; Balmain, Pierre, 1914-1982; Barney, Natalie Clifford, 1877-1972; Barry, Joseph, 1917-1994; Beach, Sylvia, 1887-1962; Beaton, Cecil, 1904-1980; Bérard, Christian, 1902-1949; Berenson, Bernard, 1865-1959; Berman, Eugene, 1899-1972; Berners, Gerald Hugh Tyrwhitt-Wilson, Baron, 1883-1950; Bonney, Thérèse, 1894-1978; Bowles, Paul, 1910-1999; Bradley, William Aspenwall, 1878-1939; Braque, Georges, 1882-1963; Breon, John Wallace, 1923-1984; Brinnin, John Malcolm, 1916-1998; Bromfield, Louis, 1896-1956; Brooks, Romaine, 1874-1970; Brown, Bob, 1886-1959; Brown, Margaret Wise, 1910-1952; Bruce, Patrick Henry, 1881-1936; Bryher, 1894-1983; Burnett, Whit, 1899-1973; Buss, Kate; Butcher, Fanny, 1888-1987; Cerf, Bennett, 1898-1971; Chapman, Elizabeth Fuller; Church, Ralph Withington, 1900-; Coates, Robert M. (Robert Myron), 1897-1973; Coburn, Alvin Langdon, 1882-1966; Cocteau, Jean, 1889-1963; Cone, Claribel, 1864-1929; Cone, Etta, 1870-1949; Cornell, Katharine, 1893-1974; Crevel, René, 1900-1935; Crowninshield, Frank, 1872-1947; Daniel-Rops, Henri, 1901-1965; Davidson, Jo, 1883-1952; Delaunay, Robert, 1885-1941; Demuth, Charles, 1883-1935; Draper, Muriel, 1886-1952; Dufy, Raoul, 1877-1953; Duncan, Elizabeth; Duncan, Raymond, 1874-1966; Eliot, T. S. (Thomas Stearns), 1888-1965; Escholier, Raymond, 1882-1971; Evans, Donald, 1884-1921; Faÿ, Bernard, 1893-1978; Fellowes, Daisy; Flanner, Janet, 1892-1978; Ford, Charles Henri, 1908-2002; Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939; Fort, Paul, 1872-1960; Gibb, Henry Phelan; Gorer, Geoffrey, 1905-; Gramont, Elisabeth de, 1875-1954; Graves, Robert, 1895-1985; Gris, Juan, 1887-1927; Grosser, Maurice, 1903-1986; Guevara, Alvaro, 1894-1951; Haas, Robert Bartlett; Hapgood, Hutchins, 1869-1944; Harper, Allanah, 1904-1992; Harrison, Gilbert A.; Hartley, Marsden, 1877-1943; Haweis, Stephen; Heap, Jane, 1883-1964; Hemingway, Ernest, 1899-1961; Hopwood, Avery, 1882-1928; Hubbell, Lindley Williams, 1901-1994; Huebsch, B. W. (Benjamin W.), 1876-1964; Hugnet, Georges, 1906-1974; Imbs, Bravig, 1904-1946; Jackson, Laura (Riding), 1901-1991; Jacob, Max, 1876-1944; Jolas, Eugène, 1894-1952; Kahnweiler, Daniel Henry, 1884-1979; King, Georgiana Goddard, 1871-1939; Kirstein, Lincoln, 1907-1996; Knoblauch, May Bookstaver; Knopf, Alfred A., 1892-1984; Korzybski, Alfred, 1879-1950; Kreymborg, Alfred, 1883-1966; La Motte, Ellen N. (Ellen Newbold), 1873-1961; Lane, John, 1854-1925; Lascaux, Élie, 1888-1968; Laughlin, James, 1914-1997; Laurencin, Marie, 1883-1956; Leiris, Michel, 1901-1990; Lewis, Lloyd, 1891-1949; Leyris, Pierre; Luhan, Mabel Dodge, 1879-1962; Lynes, George Platt, 1907-1955; Maar, Dora, 1907-1997; Masson, André, 1896-1987; Matisse, Henri, 1869-1954; Maurer, Alfred Henry, 1868-1932; McAlmon, Robert, 1896-1956; McBride, Henry, 1867-1962; Mowrer, Hadley Hemingway, 1891-1979; Nadelman, Elie, 1882-1946; Picabia, Francis, 1879-1953; Picasso, Pablo, 1881-1973; Richards, Grant, 1872-1948; Roché, Henri Pierre, 1879-1959; Rogers, W. G. (William Garland), 1896-1978; Rose, Francis, Sir, 1909-1979; Rosenshine, Annette; Ross, Marvin C. (Marvin Chauncey), 1904-1977; Satie, Erik, 1866-1925; Schwab, Raymond; Scudder, Janet, 1873-; Sears, William Paul, 1902-; Seldes, Gilbert, 1893-1970; Sitwell, Edith, 1887-1964; Stein, Gertrude, 1874-1946; Stein, Leo, 1872-1947; Stein, Michael, 1865-1938; Steward, Samuel M., 1909-1993; Stieglitz, Alfred, 1864-1946; Sutherland, Donald, 1915-1978; Tal-Coat, Pierre, 1905-1985; Tanner, Allen; Tchelitchew, Pavel, 1898-1957; Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989; Toklas, Alice B., 1877-1967; Tonny, Kristians, 1907-1977; Ullman, Eugene Paul, 1877-1953; Vallotton, Félix, 1865-1925; Van Vechten, Carl, 1880-1964; Villard, Léonie; Vollard, Ambroise, 1867-1939; Whitehead, Alfred North, 1861-1947; Wilcox, Wendell; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975; Wilson, Edmund, 1895-1972; Woolf, Leonard, 1880-1969; Woollcott, Alexander, 1887-1943; Wright, Richard, 1908-1960; Four Seas Company; Hockaday School (Dallas, Tex.)
- Writings of Gertrude Stein, 1894-1947; Series I; 39; (94 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Writings, is divided into sub-series, in which items are arranged alphabetically by title and incipit, except with Carnets, which are arranged chronologically, and with Writings of Others, alphabetized by author
  - GERTRUDE STEIN BIBLIOGRAPH
    - A La Recherche d'un peintre [Riba-Rovira]
      Related Archival Materials note
      See: Découverte d'un peintre
    - Abel, a history
      - Manuscript notebook, [1930] (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - About Laws
      - Typescript, corrected, [1936?] (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Absolutely as Bob Brown or Bobbed Brown
      See: Portrait of Bob Brown
    - Abstract painting
      - Manuscript notebook, [1946]
        In: A Message to Americans
    - Accents in Alsace. A Reasonable tragedy
      - Manuscript notebook (with loose notes), [1919] (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
        In: Bound volume 15
    - An Acquaintance with description
      - Notes
        In: CARNETS
      - Studies notebook, [1926] (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1926] (Box 1, Folder 6-9)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
        In: Bound volume 19
      - Typescript copy, corrected, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Clippings, 1929 Feb (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Ada
      - Holograph manuscript, [1908-12] (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
        In: Bound volume 10
    - Adding books
      - Holograph manuscript, [1939] (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Typescript, corrected, [1939] (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - An Address given in Cambridge and Oxford
      See: Composition as explanation
    - Admit
      - Manuscript notebook, [1927]
        In: Felicity in moon-light, a traveler's story
      - Typescript corrected, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - An advantage
      - Manuscript notebook
      - Typescript copy, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Advertisements
      - Manuscript notebook, [1916] (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Typescript corrected, n.d.
        In: Bound volume 14
    - Advice about roses
      - Manuscript notebook, [1929]
        In: Forget-me-not. To Janet
    - After at once
      - Notes
      - Manuscript notebook, [1924]
        In: A History of having a great many times not continued to be friends
      - Typescript, n.d.
      - Typescript copy, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Afterwards
      - Manuscript notebook, [1933] (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - All about money
      - Manuscript notebook
        In: More about money
      - Printed version, Saturday Evening Post, 1936 Aug 22 (Box 1, Folder 21)
        See also: Oversize, Box 168, folder 4308
    - All of it or I came and here I am
      - Holograph manuscript, [1935] (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Typescript copy, corrected, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - All Sunday
      - Manuscript notebooks (2 volumes), [1916] (Box 1, Folder 24)
        Volume 1 includes: Universe or Hand-Reading
      - Typescript corrected, n.d.
      - Typescript copy, corrected, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - All the sad young men
      - Manuscript notebook, [1945]
        In: Brewsie and Willie
    - Allen Tanner
      - Manuscript notebook, [1926] (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Typescript corrected, n.d.
    - Alma Davray
      See: Orta or one dancing
    - Alphabets and birthdays
      See: To do a book about alphabets and birthdays
    - Am I to go or I'll say so. A Play in Places
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1923] (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Typescript, corrected
        In: Bound volume 18
    - Amaryllis or the prettiest of legs
      See: Selected poems
    - America
    - An American and France
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1936] (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Typescript copies, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - An American and Paris
      See: An American and France
    - American biography and why waste it
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1922]
        In: An Instant answer or one hundred prominent men
      - Typescript corrected, n.d.
        In: Bound volume 17
    - American crimes and how they matter
      - Holograph manuscript, [1935] (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - Typescript copies, corrected, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Galley proof, [1935] (Box 2, Folder 32)
        Also contains: American States and Cities AND American Food and Houses
      - Printed version, clipping from New York Herald Tribune, 1935 Mar 30 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - American education and colleges
      - Holograph manuscript, [1935] (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Typescript copy, corrected, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - Printed version, clipping from New York Herald Tribune, 1935 Mar 16 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - Printed version [condensed as "The Pity of the Schools"], clipping from Column Review, 1935 May (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - American food and American houses
      See: American homes and how they seem AND American food
    - American homes and how they seem and American food
      - Holograph manuscript, [1935] (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - Typescript copies (2 drafts), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - Galley proof
        In: American crimes and how they matter
      - Printed version, clipping from New York Herald Tribune, 1935 Apr 13 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - American language and how it is made
      - Lecture announcement, 1935 Apr 29 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - American language and literature
      - Manuscript notebook, [1944] (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - American newspapers
      - Holograph manuscript, [1935] (Box 2, Folder 43)
      - Typescript copy, corrected, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 44)
      - Printed version, clipping from New York Herald Tribune, 1935 Mar 23 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - American states and cities
      [Full title: American states and cities and how they differ from each other]
      - Galley proof
      - Printed version, clipping from New York Herald Tribune, 1935 Apr 6 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - "American" series
      - Proofs sent by New York Herald to elicit subscriptions (from newspapers) for series (inscribed from GS to CVV), 1935
        See: Oversize, Box 168, folder 4309
      - Clipping, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Americans
      - Manuscript notebook, [1913] (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - Typescript corrected, n.d.
        In: Bound volume 11
    - L'Amerique est mon pays mais La France est mon chez moi
      - Manuscript notebook (including a copy in the hand of ABT), [1944] (Box 2, Folder 49)
        Also contains: What a day is today
      - Typescript draft, corrected, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - Typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 51)
      - Advertisement for reading/conference, [1945] (Box 2, Folder 52)
        [One has addresses on verso]
      - Printed version (as "France-Amérique"), Harmonies, 1945 Mar (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - And now. Confessions
      - Manuscript notebook, [1934] (Box 2, Folder 54)
      - Typescript copy, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 55)
      - Printed version, clipping from Vanity Fair, 1934 Sep (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - And so. To change so. A fantasy on three careers.
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1924] (Box 2, Folder 57)
      - Typescript corrected, n.d.
    - Animated
      - Holograph manuscript, [1919] (Box 2, Folder 58)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - Typescript copies (2), n.d.
        In: White wings
    - Answer to: metanthropological crisis, a manifesto
      - Holograph manuscript, [1933] (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Answer to: Why I do not live in America
      - Carnet, [1928] (Box 3, Folder 60)
        Also contains: Letter to Kristians Tonny; 2 letters to George Hugnet; letter to Jean Cocteau; sections of Their wills. A Bouquet.; personal notes and notes to ABT
      - Clipping, 1928 Nov 12 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Are there arithmetics
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1923] (Box 3, Folder 62)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - Typescript copies (2 drafts), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 63)
      - Printed version, Oxford 1927 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Are There Six or Another Question
      - Manuscript notebook, [1923]
        In: As eighty or numbered from one to eighty-one, a disputation
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
    - Arthur a grammar
      - Notes
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1928] (Box 3, Folder 65-66)
    - Arthur and Jenny
      See: Ida [Arthur and Jenny]
    - Article
      - Manuscript notebook, [1913] (Box 3, Folder 67)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
    - An artist Manguin
      See: A painter
    - As a Wife has a cow
      See: A book concluding with as a wife has a cow a love story
    - As Eighty or numbered from one to eighty-one...
      [Full title: As Eighty or numbered from one to eighty-one, a disputation]
      - Notes
      - Manuscript notebook, [1923] (Box 3, Folder 68)
        Also contains: Are there six; Wherein the South differs from the North; AND Equally so. A description of all the incidents which I have observed in travelling and on my return
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - Typescript copy, corrected (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - As Fine as Melanctha
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1922] (Box 3, Folder 70)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
        In: Bound volume 16
      - Typescript copies (2), corrected, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - At
      - Manuscript notebook
        In: Not sightly
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
        In: Bound volume 12
      - Typescript copies (2), corrected, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - At Present. Contemporaries. Play
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1930] (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - L'atelier de Gertrude Stein
      See: The Autobiography of Alice B. Toklas
    - The atomic bomb
      - Manuscript notebook, [1946] (Box 3, Folder 74)
      - Typescript, with annotations by CVV, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 75)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 76)
      - Typescript, typed and corrected by ABT, July 1947 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Attacks
      - Manuscript notebook, [1921]
        In: Vacation in Brittany
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - Typescript copies (2), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 78)
      - Typescript copy (on sheet with Jokes for Jessie, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 79)
      - Typescript copy
        See also: Separated
    - Au Bon Marché
      See: Bon-Marché weather
    - The Autobiography of Alice B. Toklas
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1932] (Box 4, Folder 80-91)
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1932] (Box 5, Folder 92-95)
      - Printed version, first installment, Vanity Fair, 1933 June (Box 5, Folder 96)
      - Proofs for newspaper advertisements, 1933
        See: Oversize, Box 168, folder 4310
      - Printed excerpt entitled "L'atelier de Gertrude Stein," Gazette des Beaux-Arts, 1934 Apr (Box 5, Folder 97)
      - Offprint - "L'atelier de Gertrude Stein", Gazette des Beaux-Arts, 1934 Apr (Box 5, Folder 98)
      - Compilation of excerpts from reviews, typescript, annotated, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 99)
      - Clippings, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 100-108)
      - Clippings, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 109-122)
      - Clippings, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 123-126)
      - Clippings, 1934-35, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 127)
    - Autobiography of Rose
      - Manuscript notebook, [1936] (Box 7, Folder 128)
    - Aux Galeries Lafayettes
      See: Galeries Lafayettes
    - B.B. or the birthplace of bonnes
      - Manuscript notebook, [1921]
        In: Currents
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
    - Backers
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 129)
    - A ball
      - Manuscript notebook, [1929]
    - A ballad
      - Manuscript notebook, [1931] (Box 7, Folder 130)
      - Typescript copy, corrected, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 131)
    - Ballade
      - French translation (by La Baronne d'Aiguy), printed version, Confluences, 1942 Jul (Box 7, Folder 132)
    - Balls
      - Manuscript notebook, [1929]
    - La Baronne Pierlot
      See: Madame Pierlot
    - Barrels
      - Manuscript notebook, [1918] (Box 7, Folder 133)
        Also contains: Rich in the City; Monday and Tuesday; The Present; Italy; The Liberty loan; Sacred fountain of Bellows; Say it again; AND Postal cards
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - Typescript copy, corrected, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 134)
    - Bartholomew Arnold or after the war is over
      - Manuscript notebook (Box 7, Folder 135)
        Also contains: Waiting for what [introducing Francis Rose] (two versions, one laid in) AND Or a history of the United States of America
      - Typescript copy, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 136)
    - Basket
      - Notes
      - Manuscript notebook, [1929]
        In: Sentences
    - Basketing
      See: Saving the sentence
    - Bee time vine
      - Manuscript notebook, [1913]
        In: Simon
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - Typescript copies (2), n.d. (Box 7, Folder 137)
    - Before the flowers of friendship faded friendship faded
      - Notes
      - Holograph manuscript, [1930] (Box 7, Folder 138)
      - Typescript copy, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 139)
    - Une Belle Matinée
      - Typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 140)
    - Bernard Fay
      - Manuscript notebook, [1928-29] (Box 7, Folder 141)
    - A Bird
      - Manuscript notebook, [1929]
    - Bird jet
      - Holograph manuscript, [1914] (Box 7, Folder 142)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - Typescript copy, corrected, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 143)
    - Birth and marriage
      - Notes
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1924] (Box 7, Folder 144-145)
      - Typescript corrected, n.d.
      - Typescript copy, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 146)
    - A Birthday book
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1924] (Box 7, Folder 147)
      - Typescript corrected, n.d.
      - Typescript copy, corrected, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 148)
    - Blood on the dining-room floor
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1933] (Box 8, Folder 149)
      - Excerpt, typescript, corrected (2 versions - first 3 pages), n.d. (Box 8, Folder 150)
      - Typescript copy, corrected, [1933] (Box 8, Folder 151)
    - Bon-Marché
      See: Flirting at the Bon-Marché
    - Bon-Marché weather
      - Holograph manuscript, [1908-12] (Box 8, Folder 152)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 153)
        See also: Bound volume 10 for other version
      - Typescript copy, corrected, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 154)
    - Bonne Année. A play
      - Manuscript notebook, [1916] (Box 8, Folder 155)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
    - A Book concluding with as a wife has a cow a love story
      - Holograph manuscript and Manuscript notebooks, [1923] (Box 8, Folder 156)
        Also contains (v. 3): Brenner and Cody as I knew them; Van or twenty years after. A second portrait of Carl Van Vechten; AND drafts of letters to Edward Utler
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 157)
        See also: Bound volume 18 for other version
      - Typescript copy, corrected, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 158)
      - Clippings, 1927, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 159)
    - A bouquet
      - Manuscript notebook, [1927] (Box 8, Folder 160)
      - Typescript copies (2 versions with carbon of second version), corrected (Box 8, Folder 161)
        See also: Their wills. A Bouquet, an opera
    - Braque
      - Manuscript notebook, [1913]
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
    - Bravig Imbs
      - Notes
      - Manuscript notebook, [1929]
        In: Evidence
        See also: Genuine Creative Ability
    - The Brazilian admiral's son
      - Notes
      - Manuscript notebook, [1924]
        In: Birth and Marriage v. 9
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
    - Brewsie and Willie
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1945] (Box 8, Folder 162-163)
        Also contains: All the sad young men (in v. 4)
      - Typescript carbon (pages)
        In: One must meditate about pleasure. Raoul Dufy
      - Page proof, 1946 May (Box 8, Folder 164)
      - Advertising flyer, [1946] (Box 8, Folder 165)
      - Clippings, 1945-46 (Box 8, Folder 166-168)
    - Brim Beauvais, a novelette
      - Manuscript notebook, [1931] (Box 9, Folder 169)
        "Motto: How could it be a little whatever he liked"
      - Typescript copy with carbon (pages mixed in two complete sets), corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 170)
    - Broadcast at Lyon
      - Manuscript notebook with holograph copy in the hand of ABT, [1944] (Box 9, Folder 171)